gopal balachandran CFO and chief risk
officer with IC Lombard Joneses now
gopal good morning thank you for joining
us growth in your focus area retail
Healthcare has been fairly strong in q1
is this growth
sustainable that's that's a great start
uh so if you ask us uh Health definitely
is one of the areas of uh preferred
segments of opportunities for growth for
ICC Lombard and exactly as you mentioned
I think we have had industry breeding
numbers uh in the context of growth
particularly when you look at for that
particular segment and for us when I
said it's a preferred segment it is both
the employer employee or let's say the
corporate Health equally is area of
focus and the other segment that you
refer to in terms of retail health is
also an area of opportunity where we
have been investing a lot now again in
the context of retail Health when you
look at for ICS Lombard even this
quarter we have actually kind of grown
faster than the industry last year again
when you look at the numbers industry
grew at roughly about 15 16% I grew at
about 177% if you look at quarter 1 our
retail Health numbers grew at almost
about 23% industry growth was about
18% uh so and that's a segment that we
are very excited with and quite happy
with the way how growth have played out
and even on the corporate Health again
if you look at I think we have again had
industry breeding numbers uh industry
grew at we have we have kind of almost
doubled the growth numbers uh when you
look at it in the context of growth for
Isis Lombard so hence uh quite excited
with the way how the investments in the
retail Health franchise is playing out
and that's an area which will be a
continuing one uh in terms of continuing
investments in the past we had a market
share on that particular segment which
was less than 3% we have been able to
kind of make an improvement thereon
currently as we speak the market share
stands improved to 3.1% but as I said
this will be an area of continued Focus
both in the context of retail health and
corporate
Health okay so balachandran um if I can
just push you a little bit more on the
mix um what is the Outlook when it comes
to health is it as big as motor for you
what do you think is going to be the
trend sure I think again as is as we
keep saying for us if you ask us all the
three key lines of businesses are areas
of focus when I say all the three key
lines whether it is motor whether it's
health or whether it is a commercial
lines all of them are clearly areas of
opportunities is the way that we see for
is Lombard and hence we obviously would
like to see growth momentum sustaining
across the key three key lines having
said that you are absolutely right uh
historically motor by the way has been
the largest contributor to the overall
revenues it's been for understandable
reasons during covid periods for two
years clearly Health displaced motor as
the largest contributing segment and as
we speak Health continues to be one of
the fastest growing uh growth segment so
hence to that extent even for us when
you look at it from a growth percentage
standpoint Health would have kind of
grown uh relatively faster as compared
to let's say some of the other lines of
businesses uh so hence in terms of mix
we clearly believe that health will
continue to grow disproportionately
faster motor in the past for us has been
a conscious call of going a bit slow
given the reasons significant aggression
that the market has been exhibiting
already we are again seeing in motor
specifically signs of growth uh emerging
back to us and Commercial lines again
historically we have always kind of
disproportionately grown relative to the
market performance hence to answer your
point in terms of mix Health in terms of
growth percentages will continue to grow
faster uh but in terms of the overall
mix my sense is it will be broadly
almost a kind of an equal split between
commercial lines motor health and a very
small proportion of our portfolio will
also comprise of
crop right and with regards to your loss
ratios your motor ODI loss ratio has now
significantly declined to about
67% what's causing this
for us claim service is definitely an
area of priority and we kind of put a
lot of focus emphasis in terms of making
sure that the experience for the
customer is significantly Superior uh
since you talked in the context of motor
I think what we have been able to
significantly Drive is uh I mean today
when you look at when an accident
happens uh many of times it so happens
the insurance companies possibly last in
the pyramid to get to know of the claim
that has happened that's a a direction
that we planning to change by which we
are significantly looking at diverting
traffic to what we call as a preferred
provider Network whereby we are able to
be the first notice of loss as and when
an accident happens and to the customer
we are able to make sure that the
experience of repair is extremely
seamless and we are able to divert that
particular claim incidence to a
preferred network of garage where both
quality of repair is quite Superior and
even the average cost of claim that the
customer is required to get exhibited to
is lower
and so there again when you look at the
PPN numbers which typically we track in
the context of non OEM claims the
proportion of claims that we were able
to divert to a preferred network of
garages that number was about 40% last
year this year the number is upwards of
65% so this as I said clearly helps both
in terms of the quality of repair
otherwise you would possibly end up in a
situation of coming back again to get
your vehicle repaired and which could
possibly increase the cost of claims and
and two as I said given that we have
been able to divert to a preferred
network of garages that we kind of vouch
for the relative average claim sizes are
also equally lower so both of this have
significantly kind of aided in terms of
trying to keep the overall uh claims
under
check definitely quarter 1 may not be
the only uh way to look at ideal thing
is should look at more over annual
Cycles but more importantly over periods
of 3 to 5
years right so the other piece is loss
ratio on the health and that has seen a
sharp rise
so fully appreciate that it has gone
from 73 to 78 but can we look at that
number quarter wise but what is the
larger Target or a band where you see
loss ratios for motor as well as
health so honestly I think the what we
have spoken about to the market is uh
from a combined ratio perspective which
has got both the loss ratio and the
expense ratio element uh put together
uh if you look at fi23 we exited roughly
at about 10 14.5% uh combined uh the
overall numbers and to the streets we
had said over the next couple of years
which is by end of fi25 is when we had
said we will get down to a trajectory of
combined at about
102% uh so that's the direction that we
want to take and the effect of this
change will be a combination of
improvements in loss ratios and equally
some of the Investments as we spoke just
a little earlier all of them will rify
in the form of improved efficiency in
operations or let's say improved
productivity now both of them is what is
going to Aid in terms of the Improvement
in combin so therefore directionally
that's the that's the path that we want
to take to bring down the combine to
about 102% by end of
fi25 uh having said that I think
particularly in the context of the
health loss ratios that you kind of
spoke about again these are quarter one
numbers uh as we keep saying if you look
at more on an year on-ear basis uh let's
say on a f year basis and even if I were
to split this number of 78.7% that you
referred to for quarter 1 this year if
you look at the corporate Health loss
ratios that number was roughly at about
92% and Retail Health within that was
about 65 now this is quarter 1 but if
you look at on a full year basis my
corporate Health was actually about 95
my retail was broadly in that same range
of about 64 65 so that range is
something that we are com quite
comfortable with whether you look at
both the segments generally we have talk
about the corporate Health loss ratio
staying in the range of 94 95% and
Retail Health we have generally kind of
talked about in that range of 65 to 70
is a range that we are quite comfortable
with uh but as I said ideally we would
want to look at it more in the combined
ratio trajectory of getting down to 102
by
fy2 right and you did speak about Opex
in the motor space so how should one
look at the overall Opex in FY 24 versus
23 because you did say as per expenses
of the management guidelines you are
within the limit
talk to us about how efficiencies will
play
out again that's a great question
because for us as we keep saying uh
there are three four key areas that that
we significantly stay focused on uh one
is obviously to kind of increase
distribution because that will kind of
significantly Aid growth and two for us
we continue to stay invested in build
investments in technology and claim
service now let me give you a simple
data point because again we keep looking
at sustainable growth over longer
Horizons and not confined to let's say
shorter periods uh if you look at for is
Lombard at the peak in terms of head
count this is way back in 2008 we had a
head count of almost about 18,000 plus
today my head count number is down to
less than about 14,000 this is after the
acquisition of bti XA that we did about
almost about couple of years back so we
have had almost close to about 30%
roughly about 25 30% reduction in head
count as we speak but having said that
if you look at the volume of policies
that we write as a company again for
that same period 2008 we used to write
about 3.5 million policies I mean last
year fi23 we exited by almost about 32
million policies so that's been a 9x
increase in policy count whereas we have
had let's say close to 25% decline in
head count over a 15E cycle which
roughly translates into an headcount
productivity of almost about 15% over a
15E cycle uh so that's the way we kind
of look at it but to get more specific
in terms of how we would see the uh
expense ratios play out again when you
looked at let's say for quarter one as I
said the breakdown of the combined is
the loss ratio and the expense ratio the
expense ratio for quarter 1 was roughly
at about
29.7 this number was lower than when you
look at quarter one uh quarter four of
last year which was at 29.9 and even if
you look at it on a year-on-year basis
let's say quarter one of last year the
expense ratios as a as a element of
combined that number was almost about
32% so directionally I think we have
been able to kind of significantly bring
down the overall expense of management
and as you rightly said uh for Isis
Lombard we have always been within the
threshold that the regulator has laid
down and as I mentioned two-thirds of
the market participants are operating at
thresholds which are much higher than
the regulatory stipulation so
directionally once that starts to see an
improvement that by itself presents
increased opportunities of growth for as
F right and therefore how is it that
should we should be looking at a
combined ratio for the full
fiscal so as I said I think we have to
as a mentioned we have spoken to the
market over the next couple of years to
get the combine down to 102 so Direction
and we as I said fi23 we exited at 104.5
so that's a trajectory that we would
want to take honestly there are a lot of
moving Parts within that we don't want
to specifically give a number out for
f24 as I said by end of fi25 we would
want to get to that 102%
number now we've seen uh Cyclones
impacting your numbers could this
possibly the year of uh alino there are
floods in North India
what what happens to the claims because
of
that so honestly again that's a great
question because uh I mean unfortunately
these days because of climate change
there has been far more increasing
number of uh events that we get to see
on a year on-ear basis uh but having
said that whenever this event happens
for that quarter you will obviously see
the loss ratios getting impacted uh
which is exactly for example when you
would have seen let's say this q1
numbers for this year we had the cycl
cyclone Joy which had a net claim impact
for us of almost about 35 crores now
that obviously impacted when you would
have looked at let's say our loss ratios
of fire and Engineering it it clearly
had an impact uh but your point on what
can possibly change in the context of
the combined ratio trajectory that I
spoke about honestly we do pricing for
some of these uh events uh in terms of
cyclones for flood losses some of the
individual Peak losses etc etc but
having said that if the magnitude of
events becomes quite severe and uh
frequent then obviously some of those
estimations is something that we will
have to recalibrate but having said that
the good part is uh I think ours is a
business which is relatively of an
annual nature and therefore if at all
for some reason the experiences turns
out to be an adverse we always have the
opportunity to go back and possibly look
at pricing the risk uh appropriately and
the impact will be something that will
be not specific to IC Lombard it will be
for the industry at large and therefore
companies which have been relatively
better for us for example if you look at
is Lombards combined has been better
than the industry combined with almost
about 15% H points uh historically uh
between 10 to 15% so therefore we
relatively have an advantage whenever
these events are far more frequent and
far more severe early signs as of now
nothing concerning is the way we would
look at but honestly too early for us to
really say whether uh these claims could
see an increase or not
okay thank you for joining in and
sharing with us the Outlook that's the
management of IC Lombard talking about
how there is a bit of slowdown in growth
for motor but they are looking at
investing a lot in retail and health as
well has not as of now displaced motor
as the largest contributor to revenues
1334 that's where the stock is currently
at